



CUSTOMER SERVICE PROFESSIONAL



+92 300 3435001



tufailsoomro@gmail.com



FLAT# E-411 RUFI GREEN CITY, GULISTAN-E-JOHUR, BLOCK #18 KARACHI, PAKISTAN

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Experienced individual with 10+ years in customer service industry seeking Customer Service Management position with your Company to utilize management experience, communication and organizational skills.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Tufail has 12 years of experience in Customer Services, Marketing and Sales in Pakistan and in UAE. He understands what wins customers, what require to build the winning team and how to lead one for optimum business growth. His management style, skills and aptitude to grasp things quickly helps companies enlarge their customer base and customer satisfaction. With his experience knowledge and background he is confident that he will be positive addition to your team.

EXPERIENCE

ibex. (foodpanda APAPC)

Team Coach - Customer Service | Apr 2020 – to date

- ▶ Responsible for performance of 25+ care agents handling chats and emails.
- ▶ Ensuring they deliver highest level of support inline 100% with client's vision.
- Keeping team acquainted with product, policies and customer centric philosophy of client
- Reporting stats to management, reducing attrition and keeping the team motivated about their work.
- Managing client relationship and ensuring SLAs are achieved on daily weekly and monthly basis.

ibex. (Careem NOW, ME & PK)

Team Lead - Customer Service | Nov 2019 – Mar 2020

- ▶ Supervising Team of 20 individuals, keeping them adherent to company policies, coaching them and ensuring they deliver the highest level of Customer Services to customers and all stakeholders.
- ▶ Working with client for continuous improvement in SOPs.
- ▶ Keeping track of agents' performance, QA, CSAT and Productivity KPIs. Help them improve in area of weakness.
- ▶ Ensuring improvement in agents struggling to deliver the required results, through motivational communication, coaching, 1on1 sessions and performance improvement plans.
- ▶ Empowering and develop team members while offering them chances to grow in responsibilities.
- ► Contributing to the process improvement. Presenting Weekly & Quarterly stats in WBR.

ibex. (Careem NOW Dubai)

Virtual Account Manager | Jul 2019 – Nov 2019.

- ▶ Managing Pool of Partner Restaurants, resolving their issues and boost their performance on Client's Platform.
- ▶ Sharing time to time Data and Analytics and suggesting improvement plans on areas that need improvement as per SLA
- ▶ Coordinating with Catalogue, Marketing and Finance department to have smooth flow of operations.
- ▶ Keeping healthy business tie ups and help vendor explore new markets.
- Ensuring Quality Standards are met and address areas where further enhancement is required.



Customer Service Executive | May 2019 – Jul 2019

- ▶ Handling all the queries related to customer, captains and merchants.
- Ensuring customer satisfaction by keeping strong inter-department and external channel communication.
- Act as a bridge between back end teams and stakeholders
- ▶ Resolve issues pertaining to the food deliveries and ensuring SLA being met.
- ▶ Training and coaching other CSEs



Able to delegate intelligently and assign duties to team members wisely

Confidence in and passion for the company



Able to use critical thinking skills to solve problems quickly and effectively

Expert in creating and using spreadsheets and data entry programs

Excellent active listening and information retention skills

QAF Closets UAE

AM Sales & Marketing | Jun 2017- Jan 2019

- Plan, organize and execute marketing strategy for QAF
- Managed Social media, website and other digital channels to generate qualified leads for the business.
- Assist CEO and GM to acquire, develop and maintain business relationships with suppliers and Vendors.
- Cultivate excellent relationships with potential and existing customers to generate positive feedbacks and referrals.
- Maintain client relationships (e-mails, calls, etc.) and develop systems to support customer service/client relationship functions.
- Oversee sales process and streamlined other processes from acquiring customer to final delivery and achieving customer satisfaction.
- ▶ Preparing, directing and reviewing pricing, proposals and final contracts are being adhered by Sales team as per company policy.
- Assist CEO in Strategic Tasks like acquiring new showroom, enabling and integrating efficient system, to improve the showroom ambience and acquiring new partnerships.
- ▶ Communicate a strategic sales vision, make effective training and coaching for sales team members on how to meet established goals.
- Co-ordinate with Design, Accounts and Logistic units to reach customer satisfaction.

K Electric

AM Customer Care | 2015 – 2017

- ▶ Customer Service Center Management Making sure that from the time customer walks in, served and leaves IBC gets a pleasant experience in terms of Service Delivery, environment and problem resolution.
- ▶ Ensuring best Customer Service practices are followed by CCRs.
- Making sure complaints are logged in system and Customer is handled as per Company Policy and SOPs.
- Daily, weekly, monthly reporting to the Management and encourage CCRs for further improvement.
- ▶ Following up with other departments i.e. CA, RPR and MNC to ensure complaints are resolved.
- ▶ Offer easy solutions to non-payee consumers to convert them to star consumer.
- ▶ Taking part in Process Improvement initiatives.



Outstanding verbal and written communication abilities

Able to remain calm and selfcontrolled in all situations

Detail-oriented and organized



Able to handle complaints in a productive and positive manner

Outgoing and engaging personality

Guru Corporation

AM Sales and Support | 2013 – 2015

- Customer Relationship Management by all channels i.e. phone and online.
- ▶ Supervising Sales and Support team, setting targets, evaluation and feedback.
- ▶ Lead generation, sending newsletters and designing marketing strategies.
- Maintain NPS to 80% Customer Satisfaction 90%, Refunds under 2% and 0% chargebacks.
- Maintain a productive information sharing system within department, and with other departments. Support SEO unit in lead generation.
- ▶ Ensure the team is updated with market trends and arrange training if required.

TeraData (PIA)

Travel Consultant | 2009 - 2010

- Online reservations for airline customers.
- ▶ Handling general queries regarding airline operations.
- ▶ Voice, email and chat communication with airline customers.
- ▶ Ensuring maintenance of performance and quality standards.
- ▶ Handling of PIA Frequent Flyer Program members.

Mobilink (Jazz)

Quality Assurance Supervisor | 2006 - 2008

- ▶ Evaluating Customer Service Representatives performance on Daily/Weekly/Monthly basis.
- Ensuring that proper procedures of feedback are being followed.
- Monitoring and Promoting excellent communication and interpersonal skills among team members and contact center executives.
- Generating quality scoring report and communicating statistics to management.
- ▶ Coordinating and conducting sessions with team to ensure that proper feedback and inputs are given.

EDUCATION

MUHAMMAD ALI JINNAH UNIVERSITY

MBA Marketing - GPA 3.36

Year of completion 2012

SHAH ABDUL LATIF UNIVERSITY

MA Economics – 2nd Division

Year of completion 2009

SHAH ABDUL LATIF UNIVERSITY

BA Economics – 2nd Division

Year of completion 2005

REFERENCES

Shall be provided if required.